Aboth
-------------------------------- 2,000 Years Ago --------------------------------
Retreat! Retreat!
（兵士）
退避！　退避せよ～！
国王様！　お逃げください！
You must flee immediately, Your Majesty!
Wytearp
-------------------------------- Present Day --------------------------------
Favaro!
ファバロ～！
（酒場の女たち）
ハア… ハア…
（無法者Ａ）
待て こら！
Get back here, damn it!
（無法者Ｂ）
おいおい 逃げんなよ！
Hey, now! Don't go runnin' off!
姑息(こそく)な！
Coward!
Bye-bye!
だっ！　おわ…
マジか？　マジか おい… おい！
Whoa! Hey! Not cool!
うっそだろ～
Are you kidding me?
（カイザル）
ファバロ～！
Favaro!
おっ カイザル ようこそ
Oh, Kaisar! Welcome aboard!
Just check out this view!
ここは見晴らしがいいぞ
（無法者Ａ）
逃げれねえよ
You ain't goin' nowhere now.
I LOVE YOU, MARY
From my heart to yours, Kaisar!
カイザル 俺からの気持ちだ
貴様の施しは受けん！
I refuse your offering!
カイザル １つ忠告したいんだが…
I have a bit of advice for you, Kaisar!
黙れ ファバロ
Silence, Favaro!
I'll lend no ear to your depraved nonsense!
外道の戯言(ざれごと)など聞くつもりはない
そういうとこだよ お前の欠点は
Y'know what your weakness is? That attitude.
とにかく視野が狭い
You have such a narrow view of things.
もっと周りに目を向けない…
You need to look at the big picture.
ぐわっ！
あっ 例えば後ろとか
And what's behind you.
残念だ
Oh, well.
（酒場の女Ｂ）
いやあ！　誰か助けて！
Someone, help!
Let go of me!
（酒場の女Ａ）
放してよ！
（無法者Ｂ）
うるせえ 静かにしろ　誰も助け…
Quit your yappin'. Ain't no one comin' to help you.
（ファバロ）
わっ？　ひっ… ヤバ
Crap!
（無法者たち）
誰だ おめえは！
うわあ！
マジ ヤバい…
This is seriously bad!
（無法者Ａ）
おい！　なんだ てめえは？
Hey!
Who the hell are you?
You here to save the broads?
（無法者Ｂ）
女 助けに来たのか？
Huh? They ran off!
あれ？　いねえ！
They better not have, you dumbass!
“いねえ”じゃねえだろ
このバカ！
（ファバロ）あ～
（無法者Ａ）あん？
（ファバロ）
いや～ もろもろ申し訳ない
Whew. Sorry about that.
That wristband...
（無法者Ａ）
その腕輪…
Oh, you mean this?
（ファバロ）
あ… この腕輪？
（無法者Ａ）
賞金稼ぎか！
You're a bounty hunter!
Favaro!
（カイザル）
ファバロ～！
A prince on a white horse now?
おいおい 今日は何なんだ？
This day just keeps getting crazier.
今度は白馬の王子かよ
No, he's a bounty hunter too!
いや こいつも…
賞金稼ぎだ！
（ファバロ）
うお… ハッハ！
Stop!
（カイザル）
待て！
（ファバロ）
おい！
Hey! Keep wasting time on me and your prey'll get away!
こんなことしてっと
せっかくの賞金首が逃げちまうぞ
黙れ！
Silence! Whose fault is it that I'm now a wretched bounty hunter?
私が
賞金稼ぎになど身をやつしたのは
誰のせいだと思っている？
全ては…
This is all—
ああ 全ては俺のせいって…
Yeah!
Pin all the blame on me, why don't ya?!
言うんだろ！
（発射音）
（男）
わあっ！
とことん姑息な…
You're a monster!
Stop, Barina Chall Lidfard!
（カイザル）
と… 止まれ！
バリーナ･シャル･リドファルド！
バレレ～ シャレ ドレミファ？
Barele Shale Doremifa...
Now that's the stuff!
いい酒 置いてんな
Hey!
おい！
Don't worry about your place.
店の修理代なら心配すんな
His bounty'll cover the damage.
そいつの首で払うさ
この酒代もな
And my tab.
それ マジか？
You sure 'bout that?
マジだ
I'm sure.
（無法者Ａ）
ヤベえぞ
このまま手ぶらで帰ってみろ
This is bad. If we return empty-handed now...
間違いなく…
（３人）
ガース様に殺される！
Sir Garth's gonna kill us for sure!
The horses ran off!
馬 逃げちまったぜ
（無法者Ａ）
おい！　なんだ ありゃ？
Whoa! What's that?
（無法者Ａ）
女？
A girl?
ところで お… お前 誰だ？
U-Uh, who are you?
てか なんで裸なんだ！
And why are you naked?
Did you fall from the sky?
（無法者Ｂ）
空から来たのか？
（無法者Ｃ）
バカか！
なんで女が空から来んだよ
You idiot! Why would a girl fall from the sky?
（無法者Ｂ）
バカって言うなよ
Don't call me an idiot!
おい！　聞いてんのか？
Hey! You listening?
（アーミラ）
羅針盤が壊れた…
ヘルヘイムに行けない
The compass is broken.
I can't return to Helheim.
What are you talking about?
（無法者Ａ）
なに言ってんだ？
Whatever!
まっ いいか
We got our gift for the boss.
（無法者Ｂ）
ボスへの土産はできたな
（無法者Ｃ）
その前に もう少し
よく調べておくか
But let's take a closer look at the merchandise first!
（ガース）
女は まだか！
I want my girls! Now!
（無法者Ｄ）
ボス 今朝 この町に
賞金稼ぎが現れたとか
Boss, I heard a bounty hunter was in town this morning.
女を調達に出た連中が戻らな…
Maybe he's the reason—
Bring this bounty hunter to me!
（ガース）
今すぐ そいつを探し出せ
No need!
（ファバロ）
その必要はないぜ！
俺が その賞金稼ぎだ
I'm already here.
Hilarious.
（ガース）
面白(おもしれ)え…
Slaughter 'im.
ぶち殺せ
Bastard!
野郎！
Huh?
（無法者たち）
あれ？　どこだ？
Where'd he go?
（ガース）下だ！
（無法者たち）うわっ…
Look down!
Huh? Down?
（ファバロ）
ぐっ… いって～！
You're pretty good.
（ガース）
やるじゃねえか
シャバル･セタ･ルゲ…
Shabale Seta Ruge...
召喚魔法か
A summoning spell, huh?
Seems you've left me no choice.
なら こっちは…
あっ… 追え！
After him!
（デーモンたち）
ガルル…
What happened to...
さっきの…
ゴホッ ゴホッ
Wh-What happened to...
さっきの…
What happened to all your
huff and puff, bounty hunter?
さっきの勢いは どうした
賞金稼ぎ！
Huh. Strange, don't you think?
お～い 変だと思わねえか？
Where'd these puddles come from even though it hasn't rained a drop?
雨も降ってねえのに なんで
そんなに水たまりがあんだろ～ね？
Hell if I know! Burn him to a crisp!
知るか！
おら 焼き殺せ！
どうしたんだ？
What? How?
（ファバロ）
たは～！　すまん
So sorry!
The plants looked dry and I had no water,
so I gave 'em some high-grade alcohol instead.
草 乾燥してっから…
水じゃねえけど
純度の高い酒をくれてやった
てめえ 知ってやがったのか？
炎の攻撃を
You wretch. You knew they could attack with fire?
はい
Of course! Now let me give you a piece of advice.
１つ忠告させてもらう
It's best not to keep talkative pets.
おしゃべりなペットは
飼わないほうがいい
てめえ～！
Bastard!
You... dirty scoundrel...
なんて こずるい野郎…
こずるい… お前の運の悪さを恨め
Dirty? If anything, your bad luck is to blame.
シール･ソー･ケトム
Seel Soh Cetom.
フン！
That makes twenty now.
これで20人目だ
ったく…
Ugh.
Plastered again?
ま～た
酔い潰れてやがるぜ
Bacchus!
（ハンサ）
バッカス！
早く起きてください
Please wake up! You have a visitor!
お客様ですよ
Huh?
Get off my back! Don't you know who I am?
うるせえな！
俺を誰だと思ってやがる
A god, yeah?
（ファバロ）
神様だろ？
Maybe you should start watching how much you drink.
そろそろ
気を使ったほうがいいんじゃね？
It can't be all that good for you.
体 悪くすんぞ
Man, it always weirds me out how different it is on the inside.
つ～か 相変わらず
外見と中身が合ってねえな
Don't come bargin' in and complainin'!
勝手に乗ってきて
文句言うんじゃねえや
Here ya go. Today's catch.
（ファバロ）
ほらよ 今日の獲物だ
Here ya go, Bomber Head. 800 Rupies.
んじゃ ボンバーヘッド 800ルピだ
Don't call me Bomber Head.
ボンバーヘッド言うな！
And why'd you only give me half?!
てか なんで半額なんだよ！
I'm supposed to get 1,600 Rupies!
報酬は1600ルピのはずだろ？
Shaddap! Don't you know who—
（バッカス）
うっせえ！　俺を誰だと…
うっぷ…
Whoa, now.
（ファバロ）
おい…
Don't you dare. Don't you dare barf.
吐くなよ？
このタイミングで吐くなよ？
（いびき）
（ハンサ）くわ～
You passed out?
（ファバロ）
寝んのかよ！
賞金は
その日のうちに使いきるのが
It's my policy to spend all of my day's earnings!
俺のポリシーだ！
Let's drink the house down! No one's sleepin' tonight!
さあ じゃんじゃん飲もうぜ！
今夜は寝かせねえぞ！
You must be really tough!
（酒場の女Ａ）
あんた とっても強いのね
I guess. Today does mark my...
まあな
俺が倒した賞金首は…
two hundredth bounty collected.
今日で200人目だ
Wow!
（酒場の女Ｂ）
すご～い！
Say, what kind of people have you run into?
ねえ 今まで どんな相手がいたの？
Scoundrels that'd make a beautiful girl like you...
お前みたいな かわいい女を
泣かせる…
burst into tears.
悪党とか？
What towns have you been to?
どんな町を旅してきたの？
Cities brimming with beautiful ladies...
お前みたいな
すてきなレディーが…
much like yourself.
いる町とか？
Oh, it's girls this, girls that...
（酒場の女Ｃ）
女のことばっか
Women are monsters!
（ファバロ）
女は魔物だ！
And my journeys take me to lands unknown!
俺の旅は未開の地へと行く！
My next stop is Helheim in the far north!
次の地は
極北“ヘルヘイム”へ向かう！
The far north? Where again?
（酒場の女Ｃ）
極北？　どこ それ？
Helheim!
（ファバロ）
ヘルヘイム！
Helheim?
ヘルヘイム？
What, you've never heard of it?
なんだ 知らねえのか？
I've heard of it.
聞いたことあるよ
They say it's a land covered in snow and ice.
一面が雪と氷の世界だとか
言ってたなあ
Yeah, it's a terrifying place.
（ファバロ）
ああ 恐ろしい場所さ
Not only that, countless warriors and bounty hunters have perished on the perilous path there!
しかも
そこまでの道は危険にあふれ
何人もの勇者や賞金稼ぎが
命を落としたという
Scary!
（酒場の女たち）
こわ～い！
Not me, though! I've made it there!
（ファバロ）
けれども 俺は たどりついた！
'Cause I got me a special shortcut!
特別な近道を知ってたからな
A shortcut... to Helheim?
ヘルヘイムへの… 近道
Oops.
（カイザル）
おっと…
My apologies.
すまない
Such an unusual design.
変わった模様だ
Are you from another land?
異国の者か？
Are you lost, perchance?
もしかして 道にでも迷ったか？
I've already found a guide, actually.
道案内なら もう見つけた
（ファバロ）
ダッハッハッハ！
Yo. Took you long enough.
よお 遅かったな
Find your horse, Hammer Head?
馬は見つかったか？
ハンマーヘッド
My name is Kaisar!
カイザルだ！
（ファバロ）
んあ～ その顔は残念っぽいな
I'll take that as a "no."
Too bad. It was a nice horse.
いい馬だったのに
Indeed.
Barina Chall Lidfard was all that remained of my family fortune.
バリーナ･シャル･リドファルドは
私にとって
我が家の最後の財産だった
And, once again...
それを…
You took that away from me!
またしても貴様が！
Favaro!
ファバロ！
Now, now, now!
Don't be like that, man.
そう かっかしなさんなって
Hey, everyone! This guy's way richer and more charitable than me!
みんな！
こいつは俺より金持ちで気前がいい
Let's all accept his generosity tonight!
今夜は こいつにも
ごちそうになろうじゃねえか！
（カイザル）
おまっ…
Hold on!
Really?
ホント？
That's wonderful!
すてき！
Come drink with us!
一緒に飲みましょうよ
すまん どいてくれ
Pardon me. Please move aside.
Oh, you're a real hunk!
あら いい男じゃない
I just love knights! They're so cool!
私 騎士って大好き
かっこいいんだもの
You ladies are too kind.
困ったレディーたちだ
（３人）
キャ～！
すてき！
うぬう…
Favaro!
ファバロ～！
Man. He just never knows when to give up, does he?
たく…
本当に 本当に
しつけえヤツだぜっと♪
（アーミラ）
君…
You, there.
What the hell?! Can't you see I'm—
（ファバロ）
おわっ！　な～んだよ ちょ…
Just hold your horses.
ちょっと待っててよ
You're... a girl?
お前… 女か？
Weird. What's a nice girl like you doing dressed up like a guy?
男の格好とは
変わったお嬢さんだな
Are you into that sorta thing?
もしかして そっちの趣味の人？
Oh, where are my manners?
ああ 失礼
Do you know a shortcut to Helheim?
（アーミラ）
君 ヘルヘイムへの近道を
知っているのか？
Huh?
（ファバロ）え？
（アーミラ）酒場で話してただろ
You spoke of one at the pub.
Ah, so she heard that tall tale of mine, huh?
（ファバロ）
そうか こいつ さっきの
与太話を聞いてたってわけか
Tell me. I must find a way to Helheim.
（アーミラ）
教えろ
ヘルヘイムへの道を
どうしても知りたい
You know of Helheim, yes?
Hmm, what to do...
（アーミラ）ヘルヘイム 知って…
（ファバロ）さ～て どうすっか
Do I make something up or make a run for it?
ここは適当に ごまかして
逃げるか
I need to get there!
Are you listening to me?
聞いているのか？
Or should I...
（ファバロ）
それとも…
Sure, I can tell you!
教えてやってもいいが
But it'll cost you, y'know.
タダってわけにはいかねえよな
What do you want?
（アーミラ）
何が欲しい？
Good question.
（ファバロ）
そうだなあ
What I want...
俺が欲しいのは…
is love.
愛だ
Love?
（アーミラ）愛？
（ファバロ）そう！
Yeah. Like, say...
例えば…
a passionate kiss.
君の あつ～い口づけ…
A... kiss?
くち… づけ？
Found ya!
（ゴース）
見つけたぞ！
（ファバロ）
んん… だよっ！　おい
What the hell? Things were just gettin' good!
せっかく いいとこだったのに！
You are such a pest, Kaisar...
カイザル ホントに…
カイ…
Huh? Wha...
Who are you?
（女たち）ウフフフ…
（ファバロ）誰？
I'm Ghos!
（ゴース）
ゴースだ！
You're gonna pay for what you did to my kid brother Garth!
よくも
俺の弟ガースを やってくれたな
Ghos? Garth? Kid brother?
ゴース？
ガース？　弟？
Ah. So that's why I only got half the reward.
なるほど！
それで
報酬も半分だったってわけか
Listen. Tell me how to reach Helheim...
君 早く
ヘルヘイムへの道を教えろ
Just sit tight. I got some
unfinished business to take care of.
（ファバロ）
ちょっと待ってな
やり残した仕事を片づけっから
Then we can have our kiss.
キスは そのあとだ
（ゴース）
バカめ！　お前がキスするのは…
Fool! The only thing you're gonna kiss... is Death!
死神だ！
（デーモン）
ガア～
It's so puny!
ちっちぇえ！
Oh, man!
おいおいおい 弟のほうが
もう少しマシなもん…
Your kid brother managed to summon way better...
でかっ！
It's huge!
Tear them to shreds!
（ゴース）
そいつらを八つ裂きにしろ！
You got some serious power there!
なかなかのパワーじゃねえか
いい解体屋 紹介してやるよ
You'd do well in the scrapyard industry!
ぐわあああ！
（デーモン）
グガア…
（ファバロ）
おわっ！
Bastard.
にゃろう～
My sword!
俺の剣！
Run, you idiot! You're gonna get killed!
（ファバロ）
バカ どけ！　殺されるぞ！
You're my guide. I need you.
（アーミラ）
君は大事な道案内だ
Huh?
That's why I will take care of this.
（アーミラ）
だから こいつは
私が… やる
What the...
なんだ…
A... demon?
悪魔？
ぬおっ！
ぐわっ！
Damn you. That was a dirty fight.
貴様… 卑怯(ひきょう)だぞ
Faking me out with that tiny monster at first was way dirtier, if you ask me.
ちっちゃいと見せかけて
でっけえの出すほうが
よっぽど卑怯だろ
So, what about you two?
で… おたくらは どうすんの？
（女たち）
あ… きゃあああ！
H-Hey! I haven't even done anything!
お… おい！
まだ 何もしてねえだろ
Yikes!
（ファバロ）
っぶねえ…
Ow, my neck.
首にきた…
A... demon?
（ファバロ）
あ… 悪魔？
どうやら…
I think I've had a bit too much to drink.
飲み過ぎたみてえだ
ハア… ハア…
Man, that dream...
なんだ？　さっきの夢…
Oh, you're awake. Good morning.
ああ 起きてるわね
おはよう
Where am I?
（ファバロ）
ここ どこ？
The pub's attic.
酒場の屋根裏よ
I found you on the ground outside.
あんた 外で ぶっ倒れてたのよ
Hauling you up here was no easy task!
ここまで運ぶの大変だったんだから
Don't you remember?
覚えてないの？
Oh.
（ファバロ）
そうか…
な～んか飲み過ぎて
悪酔いしちまったみてえだ
I guess I had too much to drink and got sick.
I had these really weird dreams, too.
変な夢も見たし
あてて…
I ran a bath. Rinsing your face might help you feel better.
お湯ためといたから
顔洗って すっきりしたら？
Sounds nice. I think I'll wash all of me while I'm at it!
いいね
んじゃ
ついでに体も洗わせてもらうや
Whoa, don't stare. It's embarrassing.
（ファバロ）
おいおい そんな見るなって
てれんだろ
A t-tail...
しっ 尻尾…
Tail?
（ファバロ）
尻尾？
Demon!
悪魔～！
（ファバロ）
悪魔？
A demon?
Where? Where is it?
どこ？　どこだ？
What the hell?!
マジかあああ！
Rage of Bahamut
This is bad! Real bad!
（ファバロ）こいつは ヤベえ！
（カイザル）どうしたのだ？
What is? What's bad?
（ファバロ）マジ ヤベえ
（カイザル）だから どうした…
I don't think I can say!
（ファバロ）言える気がしねえ！
（カイザル）え？
Huh?
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"Escape from Livian."
（ファバロ）
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
Escape(エスケープ) from(フロム) Livian(リヴィアン)
（ファバロ）言えたよ！
（カイザル）ホントだ
No, you said it!
Oh, I did.
Illustration: Niji